constitutionus.com 2001-12-01

# Virtualology Privacy Policy

**_VIRTUALOLOGY'S MISSION IS TO FOSTER AN UNDERSTANDING OF HUMANITY'S GREAT MOMENTS, EXCEPTIONAL MINDS, REMARKABLE TALENTS, INFAMOUS ACTIONS, GREAT EVENTS, NATURAL HISTORY, SCIENTIFIC DISCOVERIES, AND CELEBRATION OF INDIVIDUALS._**

We at _Virtualology ™ , Inc. ** **_ have the utmost respect for individual privacy.  We try to foster an understanding of historical events that served to protect and preserve basic rights, such as individual privacy.  Please read this Privacy Policy and understand it before you use any of the _Virtualology ™_ sites or affiliated web sites. Parents can help their children by   monitoring the use of the Internet and advise them to not provide any personal information about them or you to anyone without your permission.   When your child is online, encourage their use of a screen name that does not identify them or you.  In order for a child under 18 years of age to participate in submitting any material to _Virtualology ™_ , or to participate in any activity where personally identifiable information is collected, other than a one-time request for information, parental consent must be obtained.  This statement is to comply with the requirements of US law, so if you are resident of another country, please obtain your own advice before submitting personal information.

**IF YOU ARE UNDER 18 YEARS OLD, PLEASE HAVE YOUR PARENT/GUARDIAN READ THIS POLICY COMPLETELY.   PLEASE ASK YOUR PARENT/GUARDIAN TO EXPLAIN IT TO YOU IF YOU HAVE ANY QUESTIONS.  **

 If you have any questions, comments or complaints regarding our privacy policy, you may contact us at the following mail address:

**_Virtualology ™ , Inc. _****  
PO BOX 623   
Carnegie, PA, 15106 **

## You may also Email questions, comments or complaints to us at: feedback@virtualology.com

For general information on the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act, please see [www.ftc.gov](http://www.ftc.gov/) for additional information.  For the text of the law and the definitions used see [www.ftc.gov](http://www.ftc.gov/)/ogc/coppa1.htm.

This privacy policy applies to only sites maintained by Virtualology, Inc. and not to web sites of other companies or organizations to which we link.  Virtualology, currently,  is the operator for  \- Virtual Student Library, Inc. , Gallery of Fame, Inc., Cybernomen, Inc., Evisum, Inc. ,  who have registered or became the registrant for the names listed on the _Virtualology ™_ websites.

This privacy policy may change from time to time.  Please check back for future changes to be sure that you are aware of our most current policy. Your use of this site signifies your assent to these policies.  Your future use of this site is acceptance of any future policy in force at that time.

 Information is only collected on a voluntary basis from our online visitors and only when:

   Submitting materials for possible inclusion on a web site or URL   
   Entering contests*   
   Registering for specific promotions*   
   Surveys*   
   Registering for newsletters from Virtualology, Inc.*    
   (anticipated activities denoted with*)   
    See also “Cookies”

Participation in contests, promotions, newsletters and similar activities to the extent requiring individually identifiable information from a child under 18 years old, will require [Parental Consent.](http://www.virtualology.com/consent/) Submittals will require either proof that the submitter is over 18 years old or prior [Parental Consent](http://www.virtualology.com/consent/).  Upon receipt of a submission, _Virtualology ™_ will send a copy of the [Virtualology Submission Form](http://www.virtualology.com/studentsubmission/)

to the Teacher and the Parent, which form requires parental consent prior to submission by anyone under 18 years old, and the obtaining of a submission code by all under 18 years of age.  When _Virtualology ™_ receives an entry for a contest from someone less than 18 years of age, we will send a confirming Email to the parent’s Email address.  When _Virtualology ™_ receives a submission for judging from anyone regardless of age, we will send a confirming Email to the teacher’s Email address, as submissions must be part of a regular or extra credit classroom assignment. 

Information that may be optionally collected from all general visitors is Geographical area, age, gender, academic interests, product or service interests .  Individually identifiable information to be collected from all (regardless of age) who submit materials for review, grading and judging for possible inclusion as part of the web page or URL, which includes children under 18 years of age:

Parent/Guardian name and address (unless submitter is over 18 years old)  
Name of Child/ Submitter  
E-mail address of child/submitter and parent (if submitter is under 18)  
School in which enrolled (or home school) and its address  
Grade level at time of submission  
Teacher’s name and email or other contact information at school  
Class / Subject  
Title of Paper  
Date of Birth

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION THAT MAY BE COLLECTED , and may be made available to third parties

Areas of academic interest/study  
Areas of Products or services that would enhance the learning experience  
Areas of Products or services that would compliment educational goals  
_Virtualology ™_ sites visited  
Geographical area, age, gender, product or service interests

**USES OF INFORMATION COLLECTED**

The following information will appear on submissions and be seen by the site operator and third parties.  It will be used to separate entries from all other entries, to assure that there are not multiple entries from the same person for the exact same contest period, to notify parent and teacher of submittal and if it was a winner.  The Information will also be used to separate categories of entrants into the appropriate class level (example collegiate versus fifth grade)

Parent/Guardian name and address (unless submitter is over 18 years old) Name of Child/ Submitter (unless the teacher makes other arrangements with _Virtualology ™_ to use distinctive screen names, combining school, teacher and class name identifiers) E-mail address of child/submitter and parent (if submitter is under 18) School in which enrolled (or home school) and its address Grade level at time of submission Teacher’s name and email or other contact information at school; Class / Subject; Title of Paper; Date of Birth.

Materials submitted will be reviewed, judged, and winning submittals may be published in total or edited on the web site or URL of the topic where appropriate, and may also be published on the judging or sponsors site through hyper links.  The city and state of the winning submitters school, grade level, school name, class name, assignment and teacher’s names may also be displayed for the period of time thought appropriate by the site operators. The name of the submitter, if over 18 years of age will be published. Submitters’ names under 18 years of age will be published if the submission is not clearly and prominently marked next to the student name “Do Not Publish”, and signed by the parent.  The materials if selected for inclusion at the web site or URL will be viewed and copied by the public, in general.  The editing sponsor noted on the particular web site or URL would be the organization which will view the submissions and the personal information included on it, see the [_Virtualology Submission Form_. ](http://www.virtualology.com/studentsubmission/)

As the editing sponsor will vary but is identified with a hyper link at the page where the submission is targeted, you must go to that site to determine exactly where the information has gone, who will do the actual judging and what criteria will be used.  For example, if the submission would be about Tyrannosaurus Rex, the URL to type on your computer would be tyrannosaurusrex.org.  At that page you will find the current editing sponsor.  By clicking on the area for the editing sponsor, you will be linked to a site hosted by that sponsor which will identify who will do the judging. It is the goal of _Virtualology_ ™ to award approximately 75% of the sites to editing sponsors by September 2002. For more information click on [editing sponsors.](http://virtualology.com/EditingSponsors/)

The general information obtained at any of the _Virtualology_ ™ sites will be used by _Virtualology_ ™ to determine what additional information to include on a particular site or if additional sites should be added.  It will also be used to tailor future enhancements to the sites.

We may also use personal and general information to perform demographic studies.  By doing this, we can improve our sites to meet the needs of our visitors.  Should we merge personal information and general information, we will use reasonable efforts to maintain the integrity of the personal information.

When _Virtualology_ ™  issues a newsletter, _Virtualology_ ™ or a third party mailing out this newsletter will have access to individually identifiable information  but only for those who have sent their personal information and requested the newsletter.

Our third party partners may have useful products or services.  We attempt to limit use of your information to those services/products that we feel would be of benefit to you.  WE MAY PROVIDE YOUR INDIVIDUALLY IDENTIFYING INFORMATION TO THESE PARTIES.  You will be asked to have information about these sent to you.  As of this writing (see date at beginning), the third parties are either entities that are a University, University associated, or Museums.  In the future, this information will available to advertisers and also be sent to other third parties who will have products and services to offer.  We will limit this to exclude what we feel are inappropriate solicitations.

 We have asked our third parties to abide by our privacy policy.

Children under 13 must by United States law have parental consent to provide personal information over the Internet. We have selected 18 years of age to keep all parents/guardians involved in the learning process and encourage their children’s efforts.  Our policy is to require that all persons under 18 years of age provide a parental consent form to enter any submission and to participate in any activity that requires the disclosure of personal information.

The form found at [Parental Consent](http://www.virtualology.com/consent/)  must be completed, signed by the parent or guardian and mailed to:

**_Virtualology ™ , Inc. _****   
PO BOX 623   
Carnegie, PA, 15106 **

THIS FORM states that you are giving your consent to the collection, transfer and use of the child’s personally identifiable information.  THIS FORM states that you are giving your consent to the unlimited use, publication (in total or edited), broadcast, incorporation into websites, television, radio or other medium, of any submissions and that they may be used in any current or future advances in the state of communication that may be developed for Virtualology. YOU MAY SAY NO to having your child’s actual or screen name information published on any winning entry but we still require the student’s name for identification purposes in the judging competition.     Please send any questions about this policy in writing to:

**_Virtualology ™ , Inc.   
_****PO BOX 623   
Carnegie, PA, 15106**

**REVOCATION**

You may revoke your consent.  You revoke by completing, signing and mailing the _Virtualology_ ™ [Revocation Form](http://www.virtualology.com/revoke/) to us at:

**_Virtualology ™ , Inc.   
_****PO BOX 623   
Carnegie, PA, 15106 **

**COOKIES**

We collect and store only certain information about you.  We collect and store the internet address of the website from which you linked directly to any of the _Virtualology_ ™  sites and the domain name from which you accessed the internet, for example Juno.com, if you connected from a Juno account.  We also collect and store the date and time you access  the _Virtualology_ ™ sites

We use the information to measure the number of visitors to each site and each different section of our sites, the length of time spent at each site, and to help us make our sites more useful. General information of which _Virtualology_ ™ sites you visit will be tracked for the purpose of determining general interests. 

A one-time request for information will be processed without parental consent.   The material you submit may be seen by various persons.  Those persons my be associated with _Virtualology_ ™ or the editing sponsors.  We may enter the information you send us into our electronic database, to share with our editing sponsors..  Note that Email is not guaranteed to be secure against interception. 

It is our policy that all Email is kept in a secure Email system. As an Email address is a type of personal identification information, the access to the _Virtualology_ ™ Email system has been limited.  Most messages are deleted after a reply is sent.  In certain instances, hard copies or information or data from certain Email may be kept.  This information will be kept in a secure area and will not be used for marketing purposes. Should _Virtualology_ ™ be legally required to disclose any information so kept, it will attempt to have any personally identifying information removed from the required legal production, where possible and as allowed by the judicial system. This Email policy does not apply to any business mail sent to the company nor to Email from persons over 18 years old.

  **OPT OUT PROCEDURE   E-MAIL** You may opt out of receiving any Email from  _Virtualology_ ™ by sending an Email to _Virtualology_ ™ and stating that you want REMOVED from Email.

  **WHO WILL HAVE ACCESS TO THE INFORMATION**

The operator of the site, the sponsoring entity for the page, and the judging entity (if separate or different) for the page will have initial access to the information provided for all materials submitted for possible inclusion on the web site or URL.  If selected for publication, all of the information except the child’s/submitter’s and parents street address will be included with the publication on the internet, available for anyone in the world at large to view and copy. 

Competition and recognition are keys to this site being successful.  While we want to acknowledge the great works of our scholars of all ages, we do not want to collect or disclose any more information than is necessary to administer the activities on these sites.  We do not want to have parents feel uncomfortable.  On the other hand, the international publication of an excellent student paper or artwork at a website deserves recognition.  The site operator is willing to work with teachers and parents to protect children’s privacy through other methods that would promote fairness, competition and recognition.

If for any reason you feel that the information maintained by _Virtualology_ ™ is not correct, or you want to delete any information please write to us at:

**_Virtualology ™ , Inc. _  
PO BOX 623   
Carnegie, PA, 15106**

You must provide the initial email that you gave us to make any corrections or deletions.  We will not give out any information that we have on file without the initial Email information provided to obtain submission code.

### Start your search on [Virtualology Privacy Policy](http://search.evisum.com/xtractor.cgi?search=Virtualology+Privacy+Policy).

Other educational search engines:  
[Ask Jeeves for Kids](http://www.ajkids.com/kidsaskjeeves.asp?ask=Virtualology+Privacy+Policy&qSource=0&origin=0&metasearch=yes) \- [Britannica.com](http://search.britannica.com/search?query=Virtualology+Privacy+Policy) \- [CyberSleuth Kids](http://cybersleuth-kids.com/cgi-bin/search/hyperseek.cgi?Terms=Virtualology+Privacy+Policy&submit=Go) \- [Education World](http://db.education-world.com/search97cgi/s97r_cgi?queryText=Virtualology+Privacy+Policy&ResultTemplate=hits.hts&Collection=Education+World&Action=FilterSearch&Filter=search_filter.hts&QueryMode=Freetext) \- [Google](http://www.google.com/search?sourceid=00314383021460585509&q=Virtualology+Privacy+Policy&safe=on&sa=Go) \- [Schoolwork.org](http://freefind.com/servlet/freefind?id=6407824&pageid=r&query=Virtualology+Privacy+Policy&submit2=Find&mode=Match+ALL+words) \- [Study Web](http://www.studyweb.com/search/search.cgi?scope=Main+Index&words=Virtualology+Privacy+Policy) \- [Yahooligans](http://search.yahooligans.com/search/ligans?p=Virtualology+Privacy+Policy)   

**_Unauthorized Site:_** This site and its contents are not affiliated, connected, associated with or authorized by the individual, family, friends, or trademarked entities utilizing any part or the subject’s entire name. Any official or affiliated sites that are related to this subject will be hyper linked below upon [submission and Virtualology's review.](mailto:linkreview@virtualology.com?subject=privacy)

[Copyright](http://virtualology.com/copyright/)© 2000 by VirtualologyTM. All rights reserved.   
VirtualologyTM [Privacy Policy](http://virtualology.com/privacy/)
